Guide to the Rainbow Kitchen Records, 1974-1992 AIS.1991.10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Homestead Unemployment Center Index (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Fred Hawn (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Copies (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Citizens for Safe and Affordable Water, McKeesport, Pa. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Water, Homestead, Pa. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Veterans (Box 19, Folder 9)
- The Valley Mirror (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Urban League of Pittsburgh, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Utilities (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Utilities- Dollar Energy (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Utilities- House Fire McKeesport Boy Dies (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Utilities Struggles (Box 19, Folder 15)
- United Way Brochure (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Donor Option Rainbow Kitchen and All Correspondence with United Way (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Unions (Box 19, Folder 18)
- United Steel Workers of America Information (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Unemployed- History- Our Beginnings (Box 19, Folder 20)
- Union- Anti-Union Busting (Box 19, Folder 21)
- "The Boss" Springsteen- Letters to Us (Box 19, Folder 22)
- Unemployment Data (Box 19, Folder 23)
- Rainbow Kitchen (Box 19, Folder 24)
- Christmas Party, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 25)
- Christmas Party (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Halloween (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Christmas Party, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Christmas Party, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Articles and Flyers- Rainbow Kitchen Events (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Work/Jobs Rolodex Cards (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Member Rolodex Cards (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Suicides (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Hunger Chart (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Military (Box 21, Folder 5)
- American Profile Poster Magazine (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Unemployment Data (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Children in Poverty (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Jesse Jackson Visit (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Unions (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Articles Regarding Rainbow Kitchen (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Treasurer's Report Worksheets (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Binder of Articles about Rainbow Kitchen (Box 21, Item 1)
- Food- Rainbow Kitchen (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Food, Kitchen Food Requests, Supplies (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Food, Information, Data, Articles (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Food- Meal Count (Box 22, Folder 4)
- FEMA III Applications, 1984-1985 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- FEMA III Receipts, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- FEMA IV Receipts, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- FEMA IV Application, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- FEMA V Application, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- FEMA V Receipts, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- FEMA VI Application, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- FEMA VII Application, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Fund for Aid of Neighbors in Need (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Equitable Gas Company (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Energy Assistance, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Pennsylvania Energy Efficient Grant Program (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Emergency Help (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Economy (Box 22, Folder 18)
- Economic Redevelopment (Box 22, Folder 19)
- George DeBolt Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Clergy Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 21)
- Crank Mail (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Homestead Community Development Block Grant Program (Box 22, Folder 23)
- Community Human Services Corp., Phillip Pappas (Box 22, Folder 24)
- Christmas, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 25-26)
- Christmas Party, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 27)
- Chamber of Commerce- Steel Valley (Box 22, Folder 28)
- Poster and Button Catalogue (Box 22, Folder 29)
- Rainbow Kitchen Brochure (Box 22, Folder 30)
- Breakfast Program- Rainbow Kitchen (Box 22, Folder 31)
- Awards (Box 22, Folder 32)
- Awards- A Tribute to Women (Box 22, Folder 33)
- ARD Program (Box 22, Folder 34)
- Africa (Box 22, Folder 35)
- Action Housing, Inc. (Box 22, Folder 36)
- Energy Resource Information (Box 22, Folder 37)
- National Unemployed Network (Box 22, Folder 38)
- Newsletter, 1985-1989 (Box 22, Folder 39-43)
- Food Pantry Applications [RESTRICTED] (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Blank Job Order Forms (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Blank Follow Up Worksheet (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Blank Medical Forms (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Resumes (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Contact Information (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Petitions (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Seniors (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Filled Jobs, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Playwright Ruth Poritz (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Job Contacts (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Project Scope (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Job Order Forms, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Just Harvest (Box 23, Folder 14)
- Rainbow Kitchen Job Bank Applications [RESTRICTED] (Box 23, Item 1)
- Rainbow Kitchen Membership Lists (Box 24, Item 1)
- Rainbow Kitchen News, June and December 1989, March and Summer 1990 (Box 24, Item 2)
- Rainbow Kitchen Pamphlets (Box 24, Item 3)
- Rainbow Kitchen Newsletter, Fall 1990 and Winter 1991 (Box 24, Item 4)
- Rainbow Kitchen Pledge Sheet (Box 24, Item 5)
- Job Bank (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Job Impact (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Job Training Partnership Act (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Carl Redwood (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Sheryl Johnson (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Contract Documents, 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Job Training Partnership Act, Homestead Unemployment Center (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Disbursements (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Carol Bernick (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Invoices (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Applications (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Job Training Partnership Act Budgets, Monthly Reports, Reporting Forms (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Job Training Partnership Act- Contract Documents, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Genie Junod (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Jobs with Peace (Box 25, Folder 15)
- Just Economy (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Just Harvest (Box 25, Folder 17)
- Jesse Jackson Rainbow Coalition (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Inventory Reports, Dolores Patrick (Box 25, Folder 19)
- Infrastructure (Box 25, Folder 20)
- Hunger Action, General Information and Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 21)
- Hunger Action, Food (Box 25, Folder 22)
- Hunger Action, Pantry (Box 25, Folder 23)
- Hunger Action, Invoices (Box 25, Folder 24)
- Hunger Action, Newsletters (Box 25, Folder 25)
- Hunger Facts (Box 25, Folder 26)
- Hunger in America (Box 25, Folder 27)
- Housing, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 28)
- Homeless (Box 25, Folder 29)
- Hands Across America (Box 25, Folder 30)
- Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania (Box 25, Folder 31)
- Homestead Boro (Box 25, Folder 32)
- Hands Across America, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Papers (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Ed Asner Visit to Rainbow Kitchen (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Greater Pittsburgh Community Food Bank (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Articles about Rainbow Kitchen (Box 26, Item 1)
- Pittsburgh Magazine, January 1987 and September 1988 (Box 26, Item 2)
- Rainbow Kitchen Strategic Plan, 1987 (Box 26, Item 3)
- Rainbow Kitchen Daily Messages, October 1987-May 1988 (Box 26, Item 4)
- Rainbow Kitchen Daily Messages, October 1984-August 1985 (Box 26, Item 5)
- Children's Breakfast Program Sign-In, 1984-1985 (Box 26, Item 6)
- Monte Carlo Festival Poster, 1987 (Box 26, Item 7)
- Bob Anderson Rainbow Kitchen Notebook, 1984, April-October 1986 (Box 26, Item 8)
- Rainbow Kitchen Volunteer Badge (Box 26, Item 9)
- Bob Anderson Second Harvest Board Member Nametag (Box 26, Item 10)
- Just Harvest News, Vol. I No.3, 5, Spring 1989 Primaries, Vol. III No.3 and Vol. IV No.1 (Box 26, Item 11)
- National Unemployed Network Meeting Minutes on Tape, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- "Pittsburgh: The Human Tragedy" from Voice of America (Box 27, Cassette 1)
- Dr. Bob Gleason (CMU) talk on Economic Development in the Mon-Valley (Box 27, Cassette 2)
- Dan Sheehan on KLOS (Los Angeles) regarding Christic Inst. Lawsuit (Box 27, Cassette 3)
- Tri-State Conference on Steel General Discussion (Box 27, Cassette 4)
- Jesse Jackson Truck P.A., 3 one minute spots (Box 27, Cassette 5)
- Witness to War by Charles Clements, M.D. (Box 27, Item 1)
- Workers Viewpoint Journal 4, Vol. II No.2 (Box 27, Item 2)
- "On the Origin of the Afro-American Nation" by Robert Harris (Box 27, Item 3)
- Statement for Davis-Putter Scholarship Fund, 1992 (Box 27, Item 4)
- "Unemployed in the Steel Valley: A Community of Resistance" by Bob Anderson, 1992 (Box 27, Item 5)
- Bob Anderson Correspondence and Study Materials in a Mon-Valley Unemployment Committee Bag (Box 27, Item 6)
- Duplicate Material (Box 28)
- Slides, Photos and Negatives of Rainbow Kitchen Events (Box 29)
- Video of "Hometown Rainbow", Newspaper Reports and Pamphlets on Rainbow Kitchen, and Slides (Box 30)
- Slides, Photos and Negatives of Rainbow Kitchen Events (Box 31)
- Poster/Collage of Protests in Pittsburgh, 1980s; 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 13, Folder 1)
- Bumper Sticker: "If You Think The System is Working, Ask Someone Who Isn't.", 2.
- Drawing of Malcolm X, 3.
- Poster on the Greensboro Massacre, 1979; 4-5.
- Poster for the Council of the Three Rivers American Indian Center, 6.
- Poster for Sandi Smith, a Victim of the Greensboro Massacre, 7.
- Poster for Steelworkers Quoting Carl Sandburg's "Smoke & Steel", 8.
- United Steelworkers of America Poster- "Without Struggle There is No Progress", 9.
- NAACP Protest Poster on South Africa, 10.
- Protest Sign for Training the Unemployed, and Against the Central American Coalition, 11.
- Collage of Articles on the Rainbow Kitchen, 12.
- AFGE Local 3344 Protest Sign: "Money for Jobs, Not for War", 13.
- Protest Sign: "Self Determination is a Right, Fight Imperialism Everywhere", 14.
- Protest Sign: "We Need Money To Pay The Bills, Mr. Reagan", 15.
- Protest Sign: Steel Valley Unemployment Center Mellonomics: Hi Tech=Low Wages, 16.
- Posters: Rainbow Kitchen Monte Carlo Festival '87, 1987; 17.
- Poster on the Profit Shift for Corporations Over Time, 18.
- Poster on the Falling Rate of Profit for Capitalist Countries, 19.
- Poster on Pre-Tax Profit Rates for Non-Financial Corporations, 20.
- Poster Showing Unemployment Rates, 21.
- Poster Listing Examples of Political Activity, 22.
- Poster on Coalition Building, 23.
- Poster on How to Meet with Legislators, 24.
- Poster on How to Write a Letter, 25.
- Poster for Help with Housing Problems- Rainbow Kitchen, 26.
- Protest Sign Against Mellon Bank "A Neighbor You Can Count On?", 27.
- Protest Sign Against Ronald Reagan, 28.
- Protest Sign-"Salmon is a Green Light for Rapists", 29.
- Protest Sign, "Kick Salmon Out of Allegheny County", 30.
- Poster: "Important Volunteer Meeting", 31.
- Strike of Greyhound Bus Co. Employees, 32.
- United Steelworkers Protest in Downtown Pittsburgh, 33.
- Labor Protest, 34.
- Income Tax Breakdown for Steel Workers, 1984; 35.
- Protest Against Mellon Bank Tax Break, 1983; 36.
- Protest Sign, 1983; 37.
- Protest Against Beneficial Real Estate Agency for Home Foreclosure on Workers, 38.
- Protest Sign Against Ronald Reagan, 39.
- Protest Sign Against Mellon Bank, 40.
- Protest Sign: Steel Valley Unemployment Center, 41.
- Democratic Voting Poster/Pittsburgh Regional Power Structure, 1985; 42.
- "Stop Union Busting", Poster, 43.
- Poster: Gimbel PA Art Collection, 1986-1987; 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 13, Folder 2)
- Campaign Poster for Theresa Chalich-State House Election, 2.
- Poster for Homestead Community Days, 3.
- Protest Sign: "Do Not Vote for Reagan, Because We Cannot Afford 4 More Years", 4.
- Poster for the Arrival of Jesse Jackson and Geraldine Ferraro, 5.
- Poster by the Steel Valley Unemployment Center, 6.
- Protest Sign: "Alex, You Jerk. Can't You See There Is No Work", 7.
- Poster for Mondale-Ferraro Campaign- "Let's Take Our Country Back", 8-9.
- Rainbow Kitchen Volunteers Sign, 10.
- Sign for Homestead Unemployment Center, 11.
- Protest Sign: "Working Folks Deserve Healthcare", 12.
- Protest Sign: "Workers with Healthcare Work Better", 13.
- Protest Sign: "No Job, No Peace, No Equity = No Life", 14.
- Protest Sign: "How Many Children Will Die In Israel Today", 15.
- Protest Sign: "500 Dead in 18 Months. End U.S. Aid To Israel", 16.
- Protest Sign: "IDF Out of Palestine", 17.
- Protest Sign: "700,000 in Gaza Under Martial Law Today. Democracy?", 18.
- Sign for Christmas Gift Drive, 1988; 19.
- Protest Sign: "I'm Not Greedy, Just Needy. Raise The Minimum Wage", 20.
- "Nuclear South Africa" Pamphlet, 21.
- "Security: Merry Christmas" Pamphlet, 22.
- Poster: "Some of Pittsburgh's finest familes are at the end of their rope", 23.
- Jesse Jackson '88 Campaign Poster, 1988; 24.
- TUEL Sign Supporting the Brown Derby Strike at Monroeville Mall, 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 14)
- Fact Sheet on Consolidated Diesel Electric Co., 2.
- Clipping Collage on the Fort Pitt Steel Strike, 3.
- Mass Picketing Collage for the Fort Pitt Steel Strike, 4.
- Sign on Union Busting by Companies, 5.
- Sign on Stearns Kentucky Miner Strike, 6.
- Poster: TUEL Aids Fight, 7.
- Poster: "Blue Diamond is a Violent, Union Busting Company...", 8.
- Poster: "United Steelworkers Association-Jobs, Peace, Freedom", 9.
- Sign: Fellowship of Reconciliation-"This Kitchen is No Fallout Shelter, Peace is Our Only Security", 10.
- Poster on Food Stamps, 11.
- Poster for Women's, Infants and Children Supplemental Food Program (WIC), 12.
- Poster-"No Scab Airlines"- Eastern Airlines Boycott, 13.
- Poster for PA Medical Assistance and Health PASS Families, 14.
- Poster for the Underground Railway Theatre- "The Spirit of Harriet Tubman", 15.
- Poster- "Stop the Contras", 16.
- Poster- "March to Stop Nuclear Weapons in NYC and San Francisco", 17.
- Poster- "Stop the Great Phone Robbery", 18.
- Poster- 20th Anniversary for Vietnam Veterans Against the War, 19.
- Poster- "Service Employees International Union-We Share The Dream", 20.
- Poster-"Free South Africa", 21.
- Poster for South African Women's Day, 22.
- Poster-"Stop Bombing El Salvador", 23.
- Poster for the National Unemployed Network- "Fight For Jobs", 24.
- Poster-"End Apartheid", 25.
- Poster for the 560 Mile March for Justice by the Farmworkers Union, 26.
- Poster- African Liberation Day, 1990; 27.
- Poster- "General Union of Palestinian Women", 28.
- Poster for the National Union of Hospital and Healthcare Employees, 29.
- Poster for the US Tour of Nicaraguan Trade Unionists, 30.
- American Profile Poster, 31.
- Poster- "Namibia- 100 Years of National Resistance Against Colonial Oppression", 32.
- Poster- "Stop Apartheid- Majority Rule or No Rule", 33.
- AFL-CIO "Now is the Time" (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 1)
- Anne Markusen at CMU Ecology Conference (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 2)
- Bob Anderson on 60s and Vietnam, March 2, 1989 (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 3)
- CED/Mayoral Debate Part I and II (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 4)
- Daniel Paul Meloney Photodocumentary of OH and PA Steel Mills and Towns (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 5)
- Greensborro Massacre, African Liberation Day (P.M. Magazine) (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 6)
- Jesse Jackson Debate Rally at Convention Center Pittsburgh, April 8, 1984 (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 7)
- Jobs with Dignity, Save Nabisco Rally, February 22, 1984 (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 8)
- Labor's Corner Show #45: "They'll Never Keep Us Down" regarding the UMWA Pittston Strike (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 9)
- P-9 Meeting, Pittsburgh, April 14, 1985 (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 10)
- Paul Simon for President, "The Paul Simon Story" (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 11)
- Ted Koppel regarding Jackson-Falwell (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 12)
- Up Close with Bob Anderson and Ann Devlin (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 13)
- Hometown Rainbow (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 14)
- Ed Asner at Rainbow Kitchen (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 15)
- "Wrath of Grapes," United Farm Workers of America (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 16)
- "We're Not Gonna Take It" (Map-case 3, Drawer 14, Video 17)